And then we will simply add the ventricular system in there.
So we have already seen this stage, for now we have done this, we
have done that, okay.
You see, we will add all the segmentation, as we will see with the
different structures.
Here we can rotate it laterally, it will give you a view.
For me, what is important, you see, we can clearly see the development happening.
What is important is that you have within you a kind of movement.
Look, when I take someone, I put in the idea, I have this movement and I have a wholeness.
Even when you are going to take the feet, you will see another thing that will set in.
When we finish the whole course, you will see that the feet, you will realize
that they are connected to the peritones and that they are related to dynamics.
All of this is the same thing. That’s where it gets interesting.
mid-brain
mesencephalon
high-brain
rhombencephalon
and the spinal cord
don’t confuse it with the autochord
There, we can clearly see this ascent process here, with
all
this
hemispherization phase.
Growth, don’t forget, because we don’t see enough growth here, the overall repositioning
of this.
Subtitling ST' 501
This is where the entire process will take place.
Thank you.
These anterior neuroports, these posterior neuroports will be
a plan for dynamization.
It is from the moment I have the closure...
complete of my anterior and posterior neuroports, automatically, the
brain, restarted
through this dynamic in its development, has changed. Initially, I have
essentially
the prosencephalon, which is in there, with my anterior neuroport,
then I have the mesencephalon
and the rhombencephalon. So initially, it is simply compartmentalized like this, with, on the
inside
of this tube.
and even its vesicles, already filled with liquid.
Then we see that the process of telencephalization will
cause this process of lateral ventricles.
This is what will make it so that at this point, we have the third ventricle, the
fourth ventricle, and the lateral ventricles.
We will understand it in the dynamics of development, the telencephalon that appears.
And then we see the lateral ventricles developing.
We had the three small vesicles here at the start,
with, inside these vesicles,
inside these vesicles,
we had liquid.
Okay?
At the moment when they were not really organized.
Now the brain starts to grow,
so we will enter inside the ventricles.
Imagine, I am at the level of the prosencephalon, and I enter into the prosencephalon.
The prosencephalon bends, so the whole system pushes forward.
Closure of an anterior neuroport and a posterior neuroport
between the 26th and 28th day.
One lunar cycle.
I close.
There, growth occurs.
I have an expansion.
laterally, an opening of what?
of my prosencephalon, which does this
okay? it pushes out like this
and laterally, we see that
from one ball, it becomes two balls
okay?
and inside, the liquid, what does it do?
it follows this movement
it goes like this
and then the system, it goes backward
and it will form
my horns
my lateral ventricles
You see, they make this movement, inside, liquid only follows the movement
developmental of the prosencephalon, you see, like this.
At first, they are there, and this process we call the interventricular foramen,
which is here, you see, a little interventricular foramen,
it’s just an expansion happening at the same time as my process
of telencephalization, it forms.
the sides on both sides move outward and then follow the movement
and we see
actually that it just makes the complete movement a point of
support, and then it comes back
it's only the movement of development of the telencephalon that even has a hemisphere
that goes
a little faster than the other making this and then
joining
that moves, making a little movement like this, since I am acting
a bit.
Earlier, we do a practice, we will rework the dynamics,
we will see a bit how we can delve into the depth of the brain,
that there is a way to achieve this.
It’s like being invited to swim with the whales, don’t touch them.
We will swim with them, but we won’t go putting microbes on them.
At first, we could say that the prosencephalon is from the third ventricle.
The eye is an expansion from the third ventricle, but
we will talk about that later.
This is nervous tissue, it is not liquid.
Initially, the eye is an expansion of the third ventricle.
The interthalamic adhesion disorder.
The level of the eye is nervous tissue.
I was talking about the interthalamic adhesion.
I thought that it was precisely what has a scene.
It's a substance that connects the two thalamus.
But it forms a buoy around.
And around, there's water.
Here, especially, we will start from there now.
After, we will come back.
It's not only at the level of cerebrospinal fluid,
there's the intra-encephalic compartment
and the extra-encephalic compartment.
I can see the extra-encephalic compartment well.
When we observe the metabolic, we still discover a lot.
Later, I will show you a short film on glial cells.
I believe the people from Star Wars were inspired.
This is also important, these zones of production, you see, that we call choroid plexus,
which are found in each ventricle.
The lateral ventricles, the third ventricle, and the fourth ventricle.
Here, I’m not just telling you, there is the expansion.
The third ventricle, it's the first.
It’s not called the third ventricle.
We see the dolphins well.
This is now in your brain.
The lateral ventricles which are an expansion of the third ventricle and follow
the process.
The development of the telencephalon, the
Monroe hole, it is the McKenro hole, it is
between the third ventricle and the lateral ventricles.
The third ventricle, the fourth ventricle, the cerebral aqueduct and the brain aqueduct.
And then there, we will see, at the level of the fourth ventricle, the great traveler, the
Magendie hole,
no, Magendie, sorry, Magendie, where, there you go, we have this important expansion
toward all
my brain, toward the main opening, we can say, it's really the main opening
towards what we call.
with an important zone
there, what we call
the
Pacchioni granulations
which are the resorption sites
that occur along the sinus
longitudinal
sagittal
so you don’t have
flexion movement
cephalic, cervical curvature
pontine curvature
and especially
this great movement of hemispherization,
of tele-encephalization that reshapes
the embryo.
It's like we saw here.
Proencephalon,
mesencephalon, rhombencephalon.
And it’s mainly this part
in green that interests us to
understand this dynamic, look at the importance
of this development.
Revisiting the days will be interesting later
when we do things
synchronous in development, we will go
to search for what happens.
In carnigies or in specific months, in development, we will find
digestive or other phenomena that will occur.
This is also a reminder of different support points.
The general flexion, this is to be reviewed here again with this large
cephalization that will happen.
And one thing that will also be interesting is to remember the connections with
the tip of the onto-corn.
the supra-occiput, the basocciput, and the pre-sphenoid.
The ascent, this is really the work of this cerebralization,
it’s the ascent process, it’s all the process of establishment of the face.
So if I look at a face at first, I have a little embryo here,
and I see that I have the nasal placode developing, the mouth
forming, the heart,
and that’s true.
the very significant growth of the telencephalon that will occur
with very important support points
at the level of the future crista galli or nasion, with all the return towards the
median axis of the embryo
during growth. You will understand, and this is linked to the process of telencephalization
which has an action on the process of setting up
of my anterior midline.
Look at the growth.
huge here, and hop, all the attraction
that happens. And look at this point, it
doesn’t move.
The cerebral ascent, the process of cerebralization, and we will see
that this will influence all
the areas of the palate, which we will explain next time, with a very important support point.
here, and the development
of the telencephalon and the approach
of the palatine, the flexion
of the turbinates and the clinical posterior resultant, as we saw
earlier, a change
between the development of the brain
backward, at the same time
this corticalization, at the same time
this ventricularization.
Okay?